<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Architecture on LLMIR</title><link>https://chenxingqiang.github.io/llmir-www/docs/architecture/</link><description>Recent content in Architecture on LLMIR</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chenxingqiang.github.io/llmir-www/docs/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KV Cache Optimization</title><link>https://chenxingqiang.github.io/llmir-www/docs/architecture/KVCache/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenxingqiang.github.io/llmir-www/docs/architecture/KVCache/</guid><description>KV Cache Optimization in LLMIR KV cache management is one of the core optimizations in LLMIR, focusing on efficient handling of key-value pairs in attention mechanisms for transformer-based LLMs.
The KV Cache Challenge In large language model inference, the key-value cache stores computed key and value tensors from previous tokens to avoid redundant computation. As sequence lengths grow, efficiently managing this cache becomes critical for:
Memory efficiency Computation speed Support for longer contexts Dynamic batch handling PagedAttention in LLMIR LLMIR implements a paged attention mechanism inspired by vLLM&amp;rsquo;s approach, which treats the KV cache as blocks of memory rather than a continuous buffer:</description></item><item><title>Quantization Support</title><link>https://chenxingqiang.github.io/llmir-www/docs/architecture/Quantization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenxingqiang.github.io/llmir-www/docs/architecture/Quantization/</guid><description>Quantization Support in LLMIR Quantization is a critical optimization technique for large language models, reducing memory footprint and computation requirements by using lower-precision representations of weights and activations. LLMIR provides comprehensive support for quantization through specialized representations and transformations.
Quantization in LLMIR LLMIR supports various quantization strategies tailored for LLM inference:
Custom Quantized Types LLMIR defines specialized types for representing quantized tensors:
// INT8 asymmetric quantized tensor !llm.quantized_tensor&amp;lt;4x1024xi8, scale=f32, zp=i8, group_size=128&amp;gt; // INT4 symmetric grouped quantized tensor !</description></item><item><title>Distributed Deployment</title><link>https://chenxingqiang.github.io/llmir-www/docs/architecture/DistributedDeployment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenxingqiang.github.io/llmir-www/docs/architecture/DistributedDeployment/</guid><description>Distributed Deployment in LLMIR LLMIR provides comprehensive support for distributed LLM inference, enabling efficient execution of large models across multiple devices and nodes. This capability is essential for deploying models that exceed the memory capacity of a single device or require higher throughput.
Parallelism Strategies LLMIR supports multiple parallelism strategies for distributed inference:
Tensor Parallelism Tensor parallelism splits individual tensors across multiple devices, allowing for parallel computation of large matrix operations:</description></item><item><title>Performance Evaluation</title><link>https://chenxingqiang.github.io/llmir-www/docs/architecture/PerformanceEvaluation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chenxingqiang.github.io/llmir-www/docs/architecture/PerformanceEvaluation/</guid><description>Performance Evaluation in LLMIR LLMIR includes comprehensive benchmarking and evaluation methodologies to measure its impact on LLM inference performance across different models and hardware platforms.
Benchmark Framework LLMIR will provide a dedicated benchmarking framework to evaluate performance improvements:
// LLMIR Benchmark API (Planned) class LLMIRBenchmark { public: // Configure benchmark parameters void setModel(const std::string&amp;amp; modelPath); void setHardware(const std::string&amp;amp; hardware); void setSequenceLength(int length); void setBatchSize(int batchSize); void setQuantizationMode(QuantMode quantMode); void setKVCacheStrategy(KVCacheMode kvMode); // Run benchmarks BenchmarkResult runThroughputTest(int iterations); BenchmarkResult runLatencyTest(int iterations); BenchmarkResult runMemoryTest(); // Compare with baselines ComparisonResult compareWithBaseline(const std::string&amp;amp; baselineFramework); }; Key Performance Metrics LLMIR will track and optimize for several key performance metrics:</description></item></channel></rss>